Guide to the William Styron Papers, 1855-2019 and undated RL.01267
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings by Styron Series, 1941-1997 and undated
  - Speeches Subseries, 1942-1996 and undated
    - 1984, Nov. 18- Remarks at Paul Green/Lone Vigil convocation at Duke University, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1987, Oct. 30- Remarks for panel at Duke University, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1987, Nov. 30- Acceptance for Legion of Honor, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1988, May 15- Commencement address at Claremount-McKenna College, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1988, July- 85th birthday speech for Virginia Foster Durr, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1989, April 7- Address to Fellowship of Southern Writers, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1989, May 4 - Address on depression, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1989, Nov. 9 - Speech at Bobst Award ceremony, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1990, May 30- Graduation speech at American University in Paris, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1990, May- Presenting the Howells Medal Award Citation to E.L. Doctorow, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1990, Oct.- Tribute to Arthur Miller, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1991, Jan.- Speech for McDowell Colony fund-raiser, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1991, Jan.- Funeral tribute to Bernard Faber, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1991, Feb. 28- Tribute to Philip Roth at National Arts Club, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1991, Nov. 23- "Some Reflections on Europe and America," presented to European Parliament, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1991, Dec. 5 - Convocation remarks at Duke University's Founders' Day, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1992, Feb.- Statement on Salmon Rushdie, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1993, Jan. 14- City Lights Society address, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1993, March 28- Speech at Boston Public Library, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1993, June 1- Remarks at ABA meeting in Miami, Fl., 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1995, May 4 - Statement at 40th anniversary party, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1995, October- Remarks at Holocaust Museum, Washington, D.C., 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1995, Fall - Talk at Davidson College, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1995, Nov. 9 - Talk on genesis of Sophie's Choice, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1995, Nov. 29- Remarks, in absentia, at award for Tipper Gore, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1996, May- Commencement address at Johns Hopkins School of Medicine, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1996 - Acceptance speech for French Legion of Honor, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - 1997, Jan.- Tribute to Robert Loomis, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - Undated - Tribute to Philip Rahv; acceptance of Howells Medal, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - Undated - Fragments of 2 speeches, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
    - Abbie Hoffman, 1 folder (Box WS 16)
  - Unfinished Work Subseries, 1970-1990s and undated
    Portions of 2 unfinished novels, unfinished works on Nicaragua and Carlos Fuentes, and an unfinished memoir about Styron's father. Arranged chronologically.
    - 1970-1985- The Way of the Warrior, 4 folders (Box WS 17)
    - ca. 1980-1990- "Grandfather," holograph fragment, 1 folder (Box WS 17)
    - Early1990s- Memoir about Styron's father, 1 folder (Box WS 17)
    - Unfinished works on Nicaragua and Carlos Fuentes, 1 folder (Box WS 17)
  - Miscellaneous Writings Subseries, 1940-1997 and undated
    Miscellaneous writings by Styron, including a diary, unpublished short stories, an outline for a motion picture, essays, and unidentified fragments and outtakes. Arranged chronologically.
    - 1940, Wanamaker diary kept by William Styron, 1 volume (Box WS 18)
    - 1941, Dec.8, "A Chance in a Million", 1 folder (Box WS 18)
    - 1947, "The Brothers", 1 folder (Box WS 18)
    - 1968, Outline for motion picture about Nat Turner, 1 folder (Box WS 18)
    - 1992, Notes for1993calendar, 1 folder (Box WS 18)
    - 1993, "Live on Stage", 1 folder (Box WS 18)
    - 1997, "Grateful Words About F. Scott Fitzgerald" (Box WS 18)
    - Undated, Comments on Case Closed, by Gerald Posner, 1 folder (Box WS 18)
    - Undated, Unpublished essay on Russia, 1 folder (Box WS 18)
    - Undated, Essay on taking long walks, 1 folder (Box WS 18)
    - Undated, Essay about homosexuality, 1 folder (Box WS 18)
    - Undated, Essay on Alexander Cockburn, 1 folder (Box WS 18)
    - Undated, Fragment of "Marriott the Marine", 1 folder (Box WS 18)
    - Undated, Miscellaneous essays, 1 folder (Box WS 18)
    - Undated, Outtakes, 1 folder (Box WS 18)
    - Undated, Untitled fragments, 5 folders (Box WS 18)
- Writings by Others Series, 1958-1995and undated
  Papers and theses by other authors on Styron's work, typescripts and photocopies of works sent to Styron by other authors, screenplays of works by Styron, and limited editons of poetry sent to Styron by other authors. Includes a sermon on Nat Turner by James Cleland, a signed typescript of "La obra maestra de William Styron" by Carlos Fuentes, and autographed limited editions of Reynolds Price's "Christ Child's Song at the End of the Night," and "The Annual Heron," as well as a limited edition of Allen Tate's "All is Brillig (Or Ought to Be)." The last box contains interviews with Styron. Arranged alphabetically by name of author.
  - Aubry, Martine - "William Styron and the Aesthetics of Failure,"1976, 1 folder (Box WO 1)
  - Brunstein, Robert - "Styron's Choice," undated, 1 folder (Box WO 1)
  - Bunker, Ed - Collection of short stories, ca. 1982, 1 folder (Box WO 1)
  - Clark, Whitehurst - "Turkey Feathers," undated, 1 folder (Box WO 1)
  - Cleland, James T. - Sermon on Nat Turner,1968, 1 folder (Box WO 1)
  - Core, George - "The Confessions of Nat Turner and the Burden of the Past," undated, 1 folder (Box WO 1)
  - Elliott, Shannon - "Exploration of Grief,"1992, 1 folder (Box WO 1)
  - Fuentes, Carlos - "La obra maestra de William Styron," [1981?], 1 folder (Box WO 1)
  - Gardener, John - Notes preceding his review of Sophie's Choice, undated, 1 folder (Box WO 1)
  - Gibb, Sharon - "Styron's Turner vs. Dr. Herbert Aptheker," undated, 1 folder (Box WO 1)
  - Huffman, James - "A Psychological Redefinition of Styron's The Confessions of Nat Turner," undated, 1 folder (Box WO 1)
  - Leon, Philip - Styron bibliography,1978, 1 folder (Box WO 1)
  - Morris, Willie - Book of the Month Club News,1979, 1 folder (Box WO 1)
  - Morris, Willie - "Dear Mom, They're at it Again...," undated, 1 folder (Box WO 1)
  - Pakula, Alan - Screenplay of "Sophie's Choice,"1982, 1 folder (Box WO 2)
  - Pakula, Alan - Revised screenplay of "Sophie's Choice,"1983, 2 folders (Box WO 2)
  - Parrish, James A. - "No Home to Go Home To," undated, 1 folder (Box WO 2)
  - Peterson, Louis - Screenplay for Set This House on Fire, undated, 1 folder (Box WO 2)
  - Price, Reynolds - "Christ Child's Song at the End of the Night,"1978, 1 folder (Box WO 2)
  - Price, Reynolds - "The Annual Heron,"1979, 1 folder (Box WO 2)
  - Rockwell, Riffin - "For William Blackburn,"1973, 1 folder (Box WO 3)
  - St. Phalle, Therese de - "William Styron: Roots of Creativity,"1986 (Box WO 3)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr - "Introduction to William Styron," 1995, Feb. 1, 1 folder (Box WO 3)
  - Styron, Polly - Diary excerpts, undated, 1 folder (Box WO 3)
  - Styron, Susanna and Bridget Terry - "Shadrach: A Screenplay," [1997?], 1 folder (Box WO 3)
  - Styron, William, Sr. - "The Genesis of William Styron," undated, 1 folder (Box WO 3)
  - Styron, William, Sr. - "Stories for his grandchildren," ca. 1958, 1 folder (Box WO 3)
  - Tate, Allen - "All is Brillig (Or Ought to Be),"1979, 1 folder (Box WO 3)
  - Torck Valentine - "William Styron's Sophie's Choice,"1984, 1 folder (Box WO 3)
  - Interviews (Box WO 4)
    - Ellsberg, Daniel - Interview with Styron,1972, 1 folder (Box WO 4)
    - Kroll, Daniel - Interview with Styron, undated, 1 folder (Box WO 4)
    - Plimpton, George - Interview with Styron,1967, 1 folder (Box WO 4)
    - Rahv, Philip - Interview with Styron, undated, 1 folder (Box WO 4)
    - Shabalov, Ray - Interview with Styron,1967, 1 folder (Box WO 4)
    - Yale interview with Styron,1967, 1 folder (Box WO 4)
    - Unidentified interview with Styron, undated, 1 folder (Box WO 4)
- Printed Material Series, 1900-2019 and undated
  The printed material series is divided into the following groups: Serials containing material by or pertaining to Styron (arranged chronologically); Volumes which belonged to Styron or which contain material by or about him (arranged chronologically); Clippings pertaining to Styron and his work (some folders arranged chronologically and a few by topic); and Miscellaneous Printed Material (arranged chronologically). The William Styron Oversize Box contains other material in this series.
  - Serials Group
    - 1944-1946,Duke Archive (6 issues) (Box PM 1)
      Boxed set of Styron's copies
    - 1945, May 14, Archive Time (1 copy) (Box PM 1)
      Note in Styron's hand refers to article on J. Foster Barnes on p. 22
    - 1952, Jan., Omnibook (1 copy) (Box PM 1)
      Lie Down in Darkness (Abridged, p. 69)
    - 1954, Spring, The Paris Review (1 copy) (Box PM 1)
      Interview: "The Art of Fiction V" (p. 43)
    - 1958, Spring, The Paris Review (1 copy) (Box PM 1)
      Styron was advisory editor.
    - 1959, April6, The New Republic (1 copy) (Box PM 1)
      "If You Write for Television... " (p. 16)
    - 1960, Autumn-Winter, The Paris Review (1 copy) (Box PM 1)
      "The McCabes" (p. 12)
    - 1960, May 30, Publishers' Weekly (1 copy) (Box PM 1)
      "William Styron Writes PW about His New Novel" (p.54)
    - 1960, Summer, Critique (1 copy) (Box PM 1)
      "Styron and His Students" by Robert Gorham Davis (p. 37); "Styron and the Fiction of the Fifties" by David L. Stevenson (p. 47); "An Orgy of Commerce: William Styron's Set This House on Fire" by Richard Foster (p. 59); "Two Bibliographies: Saul Bellow, William Styron" by Harold W. Schneider (p. 71)
    - 1961, Sum./Fall, The Paris Review (1 copy) (Box PM 1)
      Poems translated by Rose Styron: Ossip Mandelstam, Marina Tsvetayeva, Andrei Vozneisenski (p. 135)
    - 1961, Nov., Esquire (1 copy) (Box PM 1)
      "Mrs. Aadland's Little Girl, Beverly" (p. 142)
    - 1962, Apr.,Wilson Library Bulletin (1 copy) (Box PM 1)
      "WLB Biography: William Styron" by A. H. Cheyer (p. 691)
    - 1962, Spring, Voices (1 copy) (Box PM 1)
      Symposium: "The Role of the Writer in America" (p. 7)
    - 1962, Nov., Esquire (1 copy) (Box PM 1)
      "The Aftermath of Benjamin Reid" (p. 79)
    - 1963, July, Esquire (1 copy) (Box PM 2)
      "Two Writers Talk It Over" by James Jones and William Styron (p.57)
    - 1963, Autumn, The South Atlantic Quarterly (1 copy) (Box PM 2)
      "The Hopeful Stoicism of William Styron" by Jerry H. Bryant (p. 539)
    - 1963-64, Winter, Mississippi Quarterl y (1 copy) (Box PM 2)
      "The Triumph Over Time: Narrative Form in William Faulkner and William Styron" by Marvin Klotz (p. 9)
    - 1965, Apr., Harper's Magazine (1 copy) (Box PM 2)
      This Quiet Dust (p. 135)
    - 1965, June, Revista de la Universidad de México (1 copy) (Box PM 2)
      "Las memorias de MacAuthur" (translated by Carlos Monsiváis, p. 11)
    - 1965, Summer, The American Scholar (1 copy) (Box PM 2)
      Styron's copy
    - 1966, Jan., High Fidelity (1 copy) (Box PM 2)
      "John Fitzgerald Kennedy... As We Remember Him" (p. 38)
    - 1965-66, Winter, Critique (1 copy) (Box PM 2)
      "Expense of Spirit: The Vision of William Styron" by Shaun O' Connell (p. 20); "William Styron's Don Juan" by Kenneth A. Robb (p. 34); "The Broader Vision: William Styron's Set This House on Fire" by Gunnar Urang (p. 47); "The Nature of Rebellion in The Long March" by Peter L. Hays (p. 70); "Robert Penn Warren, William Styron, and the Use of Greek Myth" by L. Hugh Moore (p. 75)
    - 1966, Winter, The Paris Review (1 copy) (Box PM 2)
      "Virginia:1831" (p. 14)
    - 1966, Oct., La Nouvelle Revue Français (1 copy) (Box PM 2)
      "Poussière paisible" (part I, translated by Didier Coupaye and Claude Lévy, p. 649)
    - 1966, Nov., La Nouvelle Revue Français (1 copy) (Box PM 2)
      "Poussière paisible" (part II, translated by Didier Coupaye and Claude Lévy, p. 852)
    - 1966, Fall, Partisan Review (1 copy) (Box PM 2)
      "Runaway" (p. 575)
    - 1967, Sept., Harper's Magazin e (1 copy) (Box PM 2)
      The Confessions of Nat Turner (Excerpts, p. 52)
    - 1967, Oct.7, Saturday Review (1 copy) (Box PM 2)
      "Race Riot,1831" (review of The Confessions of Nat Turner by Granville Hicks, p. 29)
    - 1967, Oct. 13, Life (1 copy) (Box PM 3)
      "The Novelist as a Rebel Slave. William Styron Goes Back to1831and the Soul of Nat Turner" (p. 51); "Novel's Climax: The Night of the Honed Axes" (an excerpt from The Confessions of Nat Turner, p. 54)
    - 1967, Oct. 13,T ime (1 copy) (Box PM 3)
      "Ideas of Hope" (review of The Confessions of Nat Turner, p. 110)
    - 1967, Oct. 16, Newsweek (1 copy) (Box PM 3)
      "Into the Mind of Nat Turner" (review of The Confessions of Nat Turner by Raymond A. Sokolov, p. 65)
    - 1967, Nov. 25, The New Yorker (1 copy) (Box PM 3)
      "The Fire Last Time" (review of The Confessions of Nat Turne r by George Steiner, p. 236)
    - 1967, Nov., Yale Alumni Magazine (1 copy) (Box PM 3)
      "Slavery in the First Person" (review of The Confessions of Nat Turner and an interview with the author by R.W.B. Lewis and C. Vann Woodward, p. 33)
    - 1967, Dec., Vogue (1 copy) (Box PM 3)
      "Styron Unlocked" by John Phillips (p.216)
    - 1967, Dec., The Hollins Critic (1 copy) (Box PM 3)
      "William Styron and Human Bondage: The Confessions of Nat Turner" by Louis D. Rubin, Jr.
    - 1968, Jan., Playboy (1 copy) (Box PM 3)
      Piece by Art Buchwald in which Styron plays an important role: "Paper Plimpton" (p. 143)
    - 1968, Jan., The Seahorse (1 copy) (Box PM 3)
      "Alumnus William Styron Tops the Best Seller List" by Neil Rabin (p.1)
    - 1968, Feb., Harper's Magazine (1 copy) (Box PM 3)
      "The Vice That Has No Name" (p. 97)
    - 1968, Apr., Harper's Magazine (1 copy) (Box PM 3)
      "The Shade of Thomas Wolfe" (p. 96)
    - 1968, May3, The Daily Telegraph (1 copy) (Box PM 3)
      "The Quiet Dust" (p. 7)
    - 1968, July 13, Saturday Review (1 copy) (Box PM 3)
    - 1968, July 20, Saturday Review (1 copy) (Box PM 3)
    - 1968, July, McCall's (1 copy) (Box PM 3)
      "The Oldest America" (p. 94)
    - 1968, Oct., Esquire (1 copy) (Box PM 3)
      "My Generation" (p. 123)
    - 1968, Summer, The American Scholar (1 copy) (Box PM 3)
      Symposium: "Violence in Literature" (p. 482)
    - 1968, Summer, Partisan Review (1 copy) (Box PM 4)
      "The Turner Thesis" by Michael Thelwell (p. 402)
    - 1968, Summer, The Southern Review (1 copy) (Box PM 4)
      "Nat Turner and the final Reckoning of Things" by George Core (p. 745)
    - 1968, Summer, Tufts Alumni Review (1 copy) (Box PM 4)
      Notice of Styron's honorary degree of Doctor of Letters from Tufts (p. 11)
    - 1968, Fall, Yale Literary Magazine (1 copy) (Box PM 4)
      "The Case Against William Styron's Nat Turner" by Robert Sussman (p. 20); "William Styron on The Confessions of Nat Turner: A Yale Lit Interview" by Douglas Barzelay and Robert Sussman (p. 24)
    - 1968, Fourth Quarter, The Whetstone (1 copy) (Box PM 4)
      "Reflections on Nat Turner" by Rev. James T. Cleland (p. 8)
    - 1968, Contemporary Writers in Christian Perspective (1 copy) (Box PM 4)
      "William Styron. A Critical Essay" by Robert H. Fossum
    - 1969, Jan 20-26, L'Express (1 copy) (Box PM 4)
      "Les confessions de Nat Turner" (excerpts from the French translation by Mourice-Edgar Coindreau, p. 92)
    - 1969, Jan. 20-Feb. 2, L'Express (1 copy) (Box PM 4)
      "Les confessions de Nat Turner" (excerpts from the French translation by Mourice-Edgar Coindreau, p. 86)
    - 1969, Feb. 3-9, L'Express (1 copy) (Box PM 4)
    - 1969, Spring, The Southern Literary Journal (1 copy) (Box PM 4)
      "The Uses of History in Fiction" (a panel discussion with Ralph Ellison, William Styron and Robert Penn Warren, C. Vann Woodward, moderator, p. 57)
    - 1969, Summer, Contemporary Literature (1 copy) (Box PM 4)
      "Negro Literature and Classic Form" by Nancy M. Tischler (p. 352)
    - 1970, Spring, The Southern Literary Journal (1 copy) (Box PM 4)
      "The Confessions of Nat Turner and the Burden of the Past" by George Core (p. 117)
    - 1970, Autumn, The Southern Review (1 copy) (Box PM 4)
    - 1971, Sept., Esquire (1 copy) (Box PM 5)
      "Marriott, the Marine" (p. 101)
    - 1971, Nov., Duke Alumni Register (1 copy) (Box PM 5)
      "Dubious Submission and Willing Fate" (interview with James Wise, p. 4)
    - 1971, Spring/Summer, The Barat Review (1 copy) (Box PM 5)
      Introduction by Nancy M. Tischler (p. 3); "A Letter From William Styron" (p. 5); "Styron's Nat Turner: A Search for Humanity" by Jean S. Mullen (p. 6); "Black and White: The Archetypal Myth and its Development" by Dalma H. Brunaur (p. 12); "Nat Turner's Mysticism" by Blair Whitney (p. 21); "Nat Turner: God, Man, or Beast?" by Patricia R. Cannon (p. 25); "Christ as Revolutionary / Revolutionary as Christ: The Hero in Bernard Malamud's The Fixer and William Styron's The Confessions of Nat Turner" by Sanford Pinsker (p. 29)
    - 1971, Autumn, The Southern Review (1 copy) (Box PM 5)
      "Rebellion of Wrath and Laughter: Styron's Set This House on Fire" by Marc L. Ratner (p. 1007)
    - 1972, March,I ntellectual Digest (1 copy) (Box PM 5)
      "William Styron on Our Literature of Collision" (interview by Philip Rahv, p. 82)
    - 1972, March, The Washington Monthly (1 copy) (Box PM 5)
      "The Red Badge of Literature" (a review of Ronald J. Glasser's 365 Days by Styron, p. 32)
    - 1972, March, The Atlantic Monthly (1 copy) (Box PM 5)
      Letter to the editor about remarks attributed to Styron (p. 27)
    - 1972, Aug., Esquire (1 copy) (Box PM 5)
      "Checking in with William Styron" by Daniel Halpern (p. 142)
    - 1972, Dec., Ploughshares (1 copy) (Box PM 5)
      "Reflections" (p. 82)
    - 1973, July 30, Time (1 copy) (Box PM 5)
      "Martha's Troubled Vineyard" (article about Martha's Vineyard in which Styron is mentioned, p. 42)
    - 1974, Feb., American Heritage (1 copy) (Box PM 5)
      "History Versus Historical Fiction" (Styron's response to an article published in a previous issue of AH, p. 101)
    - 1974, Aug./Sept., Southern Voices (1 copy) (Box PM 6)
      Styron's Copy (article by Eugene D. Genovese on the slave family marked, p. 9)
    - 1974, Autumn, The Southern Review (1 copy) (Box PM 6)
      "An Interview with William Styron" by Ben Forkner and Gilbert Schricke (p. 923)
    - 1975, Jan., The Literary Half-yearly (1 copy) (Box PM 6)
      "The Agony of a Slave Negro: Theme and Technique in Styron's Nat Turner" by K. P. Saradhi (p. 6)
    - 1975, Spring, Mississippi Quarterly (1 copy) (Box PM 6)
      "William Styron's Afterword to The Long March" by James L. W. West III (p. 185); "Afterword" (p. 187)
    - 1975, Costerus (1 copy) (Box PM 6)
      "A Bibliographer's Interview with William Styron" by James L. W. West III (p. 13)
    - 1976, Sept., Esquire (1 copy) (Box PM 6)
      "The Seduction of Leslie" (p. 92)
    - 1976, Winter, American Studies International (1 copy) (Box PM 6)
      "Race, Ideology and Scholarship in the United States: William Styron's Nat Turner and its Critics" by Okon E. Uya (p. 63)
    - 1977, Sept., Bookviews (1 copy) (Box PM 6)
      "Happy Moments at the Mailbox. Some Celebrated Authors describe..."by Peter Gardner (p. 10)
    - 1977, Spring, The Archive (1 copy) (Box PM 6)
      "An Interview with William Styron" by Marc Stanford (p. 84); "The Force of Her Happiness" (excerpt from Sophie's Choice,, p. 94)
    - 1977, Spring, Mississippi Quarterly (1 copy) (Box PM 6)
      "Discussions with William Styron" by Ray Ownbey (p. 283)
    - 1977, Island (1 copy) (Box PM 7)
      "An Interview with William Styron" by Michael West (p. 47)
    - 1978, March 14, Esquire Fort Nightly (1 copy) (Box PM 7)
      "My Life as a Publisher" (p. 71)
    - 1978, Nov. 21, Esquire Fort Nightly (1 copy) (Box PM 7)
      "Shadrach" (p. 82)
    - 1978, Summer, Bulletin of the Center for the Study of Southern Culture and Religion (1 copy) (Box PM 7)
      "William Styron on Nat Turner" (p. 1)
    - 1978, Fall, Cross Currents (1 copy) (Box PM 7)
      Issue concerning the Holocaust. Passages marked by Styron.
    - 1978-1979, Esquire Fort Nightly (1 copy) (Box PM 7)
      "Shadrach" (p. 46)
    - 1978-79, Winter, Taproot (1 copy) (Box PM 7)
      "Introduction" (p. D)
    - 1979, March, Nagyvilág (1 copy) (Box PM 7)
      "Lektorkorom emlékezete" (Elbeszélés, Ungvári Tamás fordítása, p. 326)
    - 1979, June, Horizon (1 copy) (Box PM 7)
      "William Styron. An 'Unfamous' Great Writer Brings Out a New Novel, Sophie's Choice" by Andrew Fielding (p. 60)
    - 1979, July 23, People (1 copy) (Box PM 7)
      "From Slavery to Holocaust, Author Bill Styron Makes Best-Selling Choices" by Andrea Chambers (p.67)
    - 1979, July, Vogue (1 copy) (Box PM 7)
      "The Novel of the Year: William Styron's New Novel, Sophie's Choice (p. 164); "Styron's Choice" by Robert Brustein (p. 166)
    - 1979, Aug. 27, Newsweek (1 copy) (Box PM 7)
      "Newsweek Newsmakers" (Styron mentioned among authors protesting the new American Book Awards, p. 42)
    - 1979, Aug., Look (1 copy) (Box PM 7)
      "A Conversation with William Styron" by Peter H. Stone (p. 33)
    - 1979, First Quarter, The Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America (1 copy) (Box PM 7)
      "The Second Serials of This Side of Paradise and The Beautiful and the Damned" by James L. W. West III (p. 63)
    - 1979, Summer, The Student (1 copy) (Box PM 7)
      "William Styron's Sophie's Choice: Evoking the Evil of Auschwitz Through a Polish-Catholic Heroine" by Alyce Woody and Wade Hampton (p. 40)
    - 1979, Winter, Contemporary Literature (1 copy) (Box PM 7)
      "An Interview with William Styron" conducted by Valerie Meliotes Arms (p. 1)
    - 1979 Winter, The Hampden-Sydney Poetry Review (1 copy) (Box PM 8)
      "The Writer's Power: An Interview with William Styron, James Dickey and Willie Morris" by Tom O'Grady (p. --)
    - 1980, May, South Atlantic Bulletin (1 copy) (Box PM 8)
      "Almost a Rhodes Scholar: A Personal Reminiscence" (p. 1)
    - 1980, July-Aug., Realities (1 copy) (Box PM 8)
      "In Praise of Vineyard Haven" (p. 54)
    - 1980, Sept., Saturday Review (1 copy) (Box PM 8)
      "Creators on Creating: William Styron" by Hilary Mills (p. 46)
    - 1980, Nov., Horizon (1 copy) (Box PM 8)
      "American Writers in Paris" by Ben Yagoda (p. 26)
    - 1980-81, Winter, Mississippi Quarterly (1 copy) (Box PM 8)
      "William Styron: A Biographical Account" by James L. W. West III (p. 3); "Bearing the Unbearable: William Styron and the Problem of Pain" by John L. Cobbs (p. 15); "William Styron and the Spell of the South" by Valerie Meliotes Arms (p. 25); "Styron's False Start: The Discarded Opening for Set This House on Fire" by Arthur D. Casciato (p. 36)
    - 1980, Fall, Christchurch (1 copy) (Box PM 8)
      "Styron's Choice" by Pam White
    - 1981, Jan., American Literature (1 copy) (Box PM 8)
      "William Styron and The Southhampton Insurrection" by Arthur D. Casciato and James L. W. West III (p. 564)
    - 1981, Aug. 10, Elle (1 copy) (Box PM 8)
      "Hanté par le souvenir d'une femme" by Katherine Pancol (p. 76)
    - 1981, Nov. 30-Dec. 6, Le Point (1 copy) (Box PM 8)
      "Jean-François Fogel fail le point avec William Styron" by Jean-François Fogel (p.143)
    - 1982, Jan., Esquire (1 copy) (Box PM 8)
      "The Conversation. Candice Bergen and William Styron" (p. 86)
    - 1982, Fall, The Stingaree (1 copy) (Box PM 8)
      "Christchurch to Host Sophie's Choice Premier" (p. 1)
    - 1982, Modern Literature First Editions (1 copy) (Box PM 8)
      Catalogue, Photo of Styron on the cover